[Music]
hey guys do you know that the insurance
industry is essential to every economy
to protect people corporations and other
organizations against unanticipated
dangerous and occurrence but today so
for that reason today we will have a
look on the five best insurance
companies in India but before that we'll
have to look on the insurance sector so
the insurance Market in India is
expected to reach almost around 222
billion dollars by 2026 and India is the
fifth largest life insurance Market in
the world drawing at a rate of and
growing at the rate of around 32 to 34
percent every single year so and if you
tell us about the investment of it so
every year it is going at a compound of
11 to 13 percent cagr every single year
so while keeping that is mind so we will
have a look on the five best insurance
company so the first one in our list is
LIC which is a Life Insurance
Corporation of India limited so the
current price of the company is 605
rupees whereas all-time high was 841
rupees and the low was 530 rupees in the
last one year the company has given
negative 27.7 percent returns to its
shareholders so Alaska is India's
largest and the most established
insurance provider which the nation's
government controls and the company has
a wide range of businesses and the
company has a almost 70 percent share in
the Indian market sector for the
insurance area so now let's have a look
on the fundamental key highlights of
this company
so the market cap of the company is 3
lakh 82 000 crores the p is around 10.5
The ROC which is written on Capital
employed is 149 the book value is 72
rupees and the Roe which is written on
Equity is 130 so now let's have a look
on the competitors in the current market
so this company ranked in the first
position followed by sdfc life insurance
and followed by SBI life insurance so
now let's have a look on the pros and
cons account of the company so in Pros
the company is almost debt free the
company is expected to give a good
quarterly results and the company had
delivered a good profit growth of 71.6
years in the last five years and the
company has a good Roi which is written
on Equity of around 108 in the last
three years whereas in cons the stock is
almost trading 8.3 time its Book value
and the tax seems lows
so this is the overall the first company
novelist second company is SBI life
insurance company so the company's
current price is 1218 rupees
all-time high was around 1 340 rupees
and the low was 1051 rupees in the last
one year the company has given almost
six percent returns to its shareholders
so the SBI which is the Life Insurance
Company Limited is a partnership between
BNP Paribas Cardiff a significant
participant in the insurance industry
and the State Bank of India the
country's largest public sector bank so
now let's have a look on the fundamental
key highlights of this company so the
market cap is 1 lakh 21 000 crores
the PE Ratio is around 70.8 the ROC
which is written on Capital employed is
15.5 percent the book value is 130
rupees and the Roe which is written on
Equity is 14 percent
so now let's have a look on the
competitors in the current market so the
company ranked in the third position
so you can just pause the video and go
through all the fundamental key
highlights of this company along with
its competitor so now let's have a look
on the pros and consequence of this
company so in Pros the company is almost
debt free whereas in cons the stock is
almost trading 9.3 times its Book value
the tax rate seems low the earning
includes an other income of 1758 crores
and the promoters holding has decreases
in the last three years by almost 7.35
percent
so this was the second company in our
list so the third company in our list is
sdfc Life Insurance Company Limited so
the current price is 580 rupees whereas
all-time high was around 620 rupees and
the low was 450 rupees in the last one
year the company has given negative five
percent returns to its shareholders so
the sdfc life insurance company is one
of the India's top life insurance
provider the businesses provide a broad
range of insurance options for both
individuals and group including
protections pension saving investment
and health plans so now let's have a
look on the fundamental key highlights
of this company
so the market cap of the company is 1
lakh 24 000 crores the stock pay is 91
The ROC is around 9.56 percent the book
value is 60 rupees and the Roe which is
written on Equity is almost 10 percent
so now let's have a look on the
competitors in the current market so the
company ranked the second position and
you can just pause the video and go
through all the fundamental Heritage
which is competitors so now let's have a
look on the pros and cons account of
this company so in Pros
Company is almost debt free and the
company has maintained a healthy
dividend period of 29 whereas in cons
the stock is almost trading 10 times its
Book value and a tax rate seems low the
company has a low Roi which is written
on Equity of around 12 percent in the
last three years and the earnings
include an other income of 1430 crores
and the promoters Holdings has decreases
by almost 13.4 percent in the last three
years
so this was the third company in our
list so the fourth company in our list
is ICI Prudential Life Insurance Company
Limited
so the current price of the company is
40 rupees whereas all-time high was on
608 rupees and the low was 380 rupees in
the last one year the company has
delivered almost negative 13 returns to
its shareholders so the company is one
of the India's top life insurance
provider and it is a partnership between
Prudential Corporation holding limited a
Prestige multinational Finance services
company and ICI Bank India's top private
sector bank so now let's have a look on
the fundamental key highlights of this
company so the market cap of the company
is 66 000 crores the stock p is 81.8 the
ROC which is written on Capital employed
is 8.86 percent the book value is 70
rupees and the ROI which is written on
Equity 7.37 percent
so this was the fundamental key
highlights of the company so now let's
have a look on the competitors in the
current market so this company ranked
fourth position in the list and you can
just pause the video and go through all
the details of its with its competitors
so now let's have a look on the pros and
cons account of this company so in Pros
the company is expected to give a good
quarterly results and the company has
maintained a heavy dividend period of 17
whereas in cons the stock is almost
trading around 7 10 minutes Book value
and the company has a low Roi which is
written on Equity of around 7.75 percent
in the last three years
and the earning includes an other income
of almost around 2000 crores so this is
the pros and cons account of this
company and this was the fourth so this
was the fourth company in our list so
the last company in our list is ICI
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited
so the current price is 1200 crores
whereas all-time high was around 1 350
crores and the low was 1050 crores in
the last one year the company has
delivered negative seven percent returns
to its shareholders so the company is
one of the India's top General insurance
provider and it is a partnership between
Fairfax Finance holding limited a
Canadian finance service holding company
and ICI bank which is one of the India's
biggest private sector Bank
so now let's have a look on the
fundamental key highlights of this
company so the market cap is around 58
000 crores the stock p is almost around
33.8 and the ROC is around 21.2 percent
and the book value is 213 rupees and the
ROI which is written on Equity 17.6
percent
so now let's have a look on the
competitors in the current market so the
company ranks in fifth position and you
can just pause the video and go through
all the detailed look about this company
with its competitor so now let's have a
look on the pros and cons account of
this company
so in Pros the company is almost debt
free the company has reduced debt and
the company has also maintained a
healthy dividend period of 28.8 percent
whereas in cons the earning includes an
other income of almost around 1000
crores and the promoters holding has
decreases in last three years by almost
seven negative 7.85 percent so this is
the overall pros and consequence of this
company so now this is the overall
summary so I have just particularly
choose these five Insurance sector
company which is according to their
market capitalization
and you can just go through it and just
to remind you this is not a bias
recommendation video this is just for
your general purpose so an education
purpose so do your own analysis before
investing so thank you so much for
spending some time with us we will back
with another topic till then bye and
have a nice day bye
[Music]